

♠ joachimpruegl.me

Joachim Prügl

a open for remote work

SUMMARY

Full-Stack developer with a background in electronic music, arts, multimedia design and education, combining creativity with technical expertise. Specialises in the intersection between fullstack development and UI design, with a focus on user-centric web applications. Brings openness, empathy and excellent communication skills.

SKILLS & TOOLS

Tech Skills

- HTML, CSS, JS
- Responsive Design, Bootstrap
- React, Angular, React Native
- Node.js, Express, API, JSON, Git
- MongoDB, Firebase, TDD, Jira

Soft Skills

- Adaptable, creative and naturally curious, open to new ideas
- Empathetic communication & friendlyness
- Commitment, persistence, attention to detail & self-motivation

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate | CareerFoundry | Apr 23 - Apr 24

- Intense project-based training program focused on JavaScript, HTML, CSS and most prominent libraries, frameworks and tools.
- 500+ hours of hands-on training with guidance of industry leading tutor and mentor.

B.A. Fine Arts/English | Teaching | Academy of Fine Arts & University Hamburg | Sep 15-Oct 19

- Sculture class of Thomas Demand & Ceal Floyer | HFBK
- Final Grade: 1.5

B.A. MultimediaArt | University of Applied Sciences, Salzburg | Oct 10 - Oct 13

- 1st price at the Salzburg Electronic Music Award, Province of Salzburg
- 1st price for advertising Film, Film Forum Linz (soundtrack score)

PROJECTS

Meet App, Personal Project | Nov 2023

- Developed React-based event display app (PWA) with Google Calendar API.
- Utilize test-driven development (Jest, Cucumber, Puppeteer).
- Integrated AWS Lambda for OAuth authentication. (live) code)

CUB Film Data | Full Stack Application,

Personal Project | Aug 2023 - Mar 2024

- Established a MongoDB database to store movie data and user information.
- Developed a REST API with Node.js, Express, and Mongoose, ensuring seamless database interaction.
- Conducted thorough testing using Postman, deploy on Heroku, and design two single-page, responsive frontend applications (one with React, the other with Angular) for user account creation, library browsing, and saving favorites.

(live) (code)

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Delivery Driver | Flaschenpost GmbH, Berlin | Apr 2020 - present

- Ensure timely deliveries and exceptional customer service in dynamic Berlin traffic.
- Operate vehicles efficiently, navigate traffic, and engage customers courteously.
- Achieve on-time deliveries, maintaining composure, optimizing routes, and upholding safety standards.

School Mentoring | ZEIT-Stiftung Bucerius, Hamburg | Oct 2018 - Sept 2019

- Supported immigrant children integrating and transitioning to regular school classes, teaching German as a second language.
- Engaged students through interactive teaching methods and activities tailored to their linguistic and cultural backgrounds.
- Facilitated successful transitions, equipping students with language skills and fostering their integration into regular classes.

Music Talent Scouting | Red Bull Music Academy, Hamburg | Jan 2017 - Sept 2019

- Encouraged top-tier musical talent in Hamburg to apply for global music seminars.
- Utilized industry insight and networking to identify promising musicians, providing personalized guidance.
- Elevated Hamburg's music scene internationally by increasing applications, showcasing adept talent scouting and mentoring.

Other Projects: Music Releases | Art projects | Volunteering Languages: German (native), English (fluent), Swaheli (basics)